# Daniel Lopez

#### Senior Software Engineer

Address: Portland, OR 97224

Phone: (360) 624-6877

E-mail: dlopez6877@gmail.com

GitHub: /Dlopez6877

Portfolio: projectamara.com

As a Senior Software Engineer with over 7 years of experience, I have contributed to the rapid growth of two of the fastest growing tech startups in Portland. My self-directed learning path has fueled my passion for crafting elegant User Interfaces using advanced, reusable components. I am adept in the entire development lifecycle, including version control, containerization, APIs, CI/CD, and AWS cloud services. My proficiency spans across JavaScript, React, HTML, CSS, and I am committed to continuous learning and innovation.

## Work History

#### Engineering Consultant Contractor

Ruby Washington, DC (Remote) Sep 2023 - Dec 2023

Skills: JavaScript, C#, HTML, CSS, AWS Lambda, Python, React, Backbone, Node, .NET 4.5, .Net 5.1, Google Analytics, AWS Route 53, GitHub Actions, Jenkins, GitLab, Postgres, SQS, CloudFormation, NgRx

- Conducted knowledge transfer sessions for Pure Chat applications.
- · Assisted with upkeep and management of Pure Chat application, ensuring seamless migration of all related software.

#### Senior Software Engineer

Ruby Portland, OR Dec 2020 - Aug 2023

Skills: Angular(latest), Angular Material, ASP.NET Core, Jira, Target Practice, Notion, Storybook, Agile, SQL Server, Redis, TeamCity, DBeaver, Graylog, Docker, Git, WinForms, RabbitMQ, Maria DB, NgRx

- Led integration, development, and management of Pure Chat products, reducing onboarding time through creation of architectural diagrams and troubleshooting guides.
- Established and led effective engineering team, fostering a culture of rigorous testing protocols for high-quality deliverables.
- Collaborated closely with product, sales, marketing, and business analytics teams to align technological advancements with business objectives.
- Designed and implemented company-wide coding standards and reusable components for a unified user experience across platform applications.

### Senior Serverless Developer / Consultant

Serverless Guru Portland, OR July 2020 - Dec 2020

Skills: Serverless Framework, AWS Step Functions, AWS Pinpoint, AWS API Gateway, GraphQL, AWS EC2, AWS S3, AWS RDS, SonarQube, Cloud Computing

- Improved performance of clients applications by migrating applications from on-premise servers to the cloud using Serverless framework for Infrastructure as Code and AWS Services.
- Developed detailed architectural diagrams and presented proposals to clients, outlining strategic plans for the redesign of specific sections in their applications.
- Established coding standards and patterns as a proactive measure to mitigate code smells and security vulnerabilities, informed by a data-driven analysis of SonarQube analytics.

#### Software Engineer

Zapproved Portland, Oregon Dec 2017 - June 2020

Skills: AWS SNS, AWS SQS, Angular, .NET, Swagger, Jasmine, Mocha, SOLID, AWS ElasticSearch, AWS DynamoDB, UML Diagramming, BitBucket

- Collaborated with cross-functional teams to analyze and implement system solutions based on evolving product requirements.
- Orchestrated efficient large-scale software deployments, enhancing system performance and resolving bugs. Led end-to-end development of enterprise-level greenfield project, overseeing every phase from inception to completion

#### United States Army National Guard (Washington)

25U Signal Support Systems Specialist Dec 2006 - Dec 2014

#### Education

#### Epicodus (Code Boot Camp)

2017 6-month program Portland, Oregon

- Design/Angular/.NET 6 month program where we developed applications in a high-paced environment.
- My capstone project was an Express/Angular/Node/IoT web application that allowed you to connect your device to a machine that I 3D printed and built, then select a drink and watch it pour you the drink. Repository in my GitHub.

#### Clark Community College

2008-2010 Vancouver, WA